A racing second hand, tiny shooting stars!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، شهب ساقطة
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts tired by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today's case is a Western legend! Don't put much stake in theories!
!قضيّة اليوم عن أسطورة غربيّة! لا تترك ندماً في استنتاجاتك
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Dracula Manor?!
قصر دراكولا؟
Yeah. Most of Mr. Dorakura's novels are centered around vampires,
أجل، تتضمّن معظم روايات السيّد دوراكورا ،مصّاصي الدماء كشخصيات رئيسية
so he's earned the nickname "Mr. Dracula."
لذا يُلقّب بالسيّد دراكولا
And that's why it's called Dracula Manor?
ولذا اسمه قصر دراكولا؟
Is Dorakura Daisuke a famous writer?
هل دوراكورا دايسكي روائيّ مشهور؟
He's the most popular writer in the Japan Horror Novel Association.
إنّه الأكثر شعبيّة في رابطة روايات الرعب اليابانيّة
He's even started to branch out into heroic fantasy novels,
بدأ يتفرّع لكتابة روايات الخيال البطولية أيضاً
and is gaining female fans, too.
وعدد مُعجباته يرتفع
You sure know a lot about him, Dad!
!أنتَ تعرف الكثير عنه يا أبي
Of course I do! I am a brilliant detective, you know!
!بالطبع، فأنا متحرٍّ عظيم
Ran-neechan.
ران-نيتشان
Horror Times Monthly-- Special Dorakura Daisuke Issue!
"هورور تايمز الشهريّة - إصدار دوراكورا دايسكي الخاصّ"
Shut up!
!اصمتي
There it is!
إنّه يظهر، ذاك هو
That's Dracula Manor?
ذاك قصر دراكولا؟
Detective Mori-san, right?
أنتَ المتحرّي موري-سان، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
Thank you for coming all this way!
شكراً لك على قطعك كلّ هذا الطريق
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I'm Tadokoro, I'm studying under Dorakura-sensei.
(تادوكورو توشيا (26 طالب لدى دوراكورا دايسكي
He's been waiting for you. Come this way.
إنّه بانتظارك، تفضّل من هنا
Who is she?
من تلك المرأة؟
Dorakura Etsuko (30) Dorakura Daisuke's Wife
(دوراكورا إيتسوكو (30 زوجة دوراكورا دايسكي
Oh, that's his wife.
إنّها زوجته
What a beautiful woman! I'm jealous!
!يا لجمالها! أشعر بالغيرة
Dad!
!أبي
Geez...
...يا إلهي
Old mansions certainly have a unique feel to them,
للقصور القديمة انطباع فريد حقّاً
I get a chill down my spine for some reason...
أشعر بقشعريرة لسببٍ ما
That's why I--
...لذا
Oh? Is that...
...عجباً؟ أهو
Might you be Mori Kogoro-san, the detective?!
أأنت المتحرّي موري كوغورو-سان؟
Yes... that's right.
أجل... صحيح
I knew it! It's an honor to meet you!
!كنتُ أعرف! يشرّفني لقاؤك
I'm Doi, editor in chief for Daigakkan's Horror Times Monthly.
دوي فوميو رئيس تحرير هورور تايمز الشهريّة
Oh, I know that magazine.
...تقصد تلك المجلّة
Wow, so you're the famous detective?
هكذا إذاً، أنتَ ذاك المتحرّي الشهير؟
Hamura Shuichi (33) NKU Folklore Researcher
(هامورا شويتشي (33 باحث في الأدب الشعبيّ لجامعة كانتو الشمالية
I am Hamura Shuichi.
اسمي هامورا شويتشي
I'm a folklore researcher at North Kanto University.
أعمل باحثاً في الأدب الشعبيّ لجامعة كانتو الشمالية
Oh? What sort of research do you do?
أيّ بحث تقوم به؟
Mainly... vampire legends.
بشكلٍ عام... عن مصّاصي الدماء
O-Oh. That's interesting research...
...هـ-هذا بحثٌ فريد
Say, where's Mr. Dorakura?
بالمناسبة، أين السيّد دوراكورا؟
He's in the study, writing.
إنّه في مكتبه يقوم بالكتابة
That's... a study room?
ذاك... مكتبه؟
He's right in here.
إنّه هنا
A black-out curtain...
...ستارة قاتمة
Just a movie...
...مجرّد فيلم
Mori Kogoro-san, I take it?
أنتَ موري كوغورو-سان؟
Welcome to Dracula Manor.
مرحباً بك في قصر دراكولا
Dorakura Daisuke (50) Horror Writer
(50) دوراكورا دايسكي مؤلف روايات رعب
I am Dorakura Daisuke.
أنا دوراكورا دايسكي
Octagonal rooms certainly are rare...
الغرف ثمانيّة الأوجه نادرة حقّاً
Umm... do you always dress up like Dracula like that?
أترتدي زيّ دراكولا هكذا دائماً؟
By writing while cloaked in Dracula attire as I play Dracula films,
بكتابتي وأنا أرتدي ملابس دراكولا ،وأشغّل أفلام دراكولا
I've brought many a masterpiece into the world.
أخرجتُ الكثير من التحف الفنّية لهذا العالم
So, how can I help you?
إذاً، لمَ طلبتني؟
I wish to hire you to investigate the behavior of my wife, Etsuko.
استدعيتُك للتحقيق في سلوك زوجتي إيتسوكو
Behavior? An affair, in other words?
سلوكها؟ أي تقصد خيانة؟
Yes.
أجل
I want you to find definitive proof of the affair, and the man it's with.
،أريد إيجاد دليل قاطع بخيانتها وهويّة الرجل معها
Bastard called me all the way out here just for some stupid affair...
استدعيتني لهذه الجبال لأحقّق في خيانة زوجية فحسب؟
I am willing to pay one million yen, and related expenses, of course.
سأدفع لك مليون ينّ، وسأغطّي أيّ مصاريف إضافية بالطبع
Certainly! I gladly accept the job!
!بالتأكيد! سأقبل العمل بكلّ سرور
Damn. I didn't bring any chains for the car...
يا للأسف، لم أجلب سلاسلَ للسيّارة
No worries. You may spend the night here, in Dracula Manor.
لا تقلق، يمكنك المبيت في قصر دراكولا الليلة
I think I'll do that, then...
سأقبل دعوتك إذاً
What a lovely smell!
!يا للرائحة الطيّبة
It's homemade rosemary tea.
إنّه شاي إكليل جبل منزليّ
And dinner was delicious, too! You're a good cook, Tadokoro-san!
!كان العشاء لذيذاً، أنت طاهٍ بارع يا تادوكورو-سان
Thanks to him, the lady of the house can live an easy, carefree life.
تستطيع الزوجة التمتّع بحياة هائنة رغيدة بفضله
Hamura-san...
...هامورا-سان
No, I'm studying novel-writing here, so it's only natural that I help out.
،لا، أنا أدرس تأليف الروايات عند سينسي فمن الطبيعيّ أن أساعد قدر الاستطاعة
Great. I look forward to your new series starting next month.
إذاً يا سينسي، أتطلّع لسلسلتك الجديدة التي ستبدأ الشهر القادم
Though, I must finish this month's manuscript first.
عليّ إنهاء مخطوطة هذا الشهر قبلها
Tadokoro, bring wine and a movie to the study.
تادوكورو، اجلب لي نبيذاً وفيلماً لمكتبي
Of course. What movie would you like?
حاضر، أيّ فيلم تريد؟
You decide.
سأترك ذلك لك
Say! Ran-san! Conan-kun! Want to come with me?
صحيح، ما رأيكما يا ران-سان وكونان-كن بمرافقتي؟
There's lots of rare stuff to see!
توجد الكثير من الأشياء النادرة لرؤيتها
Rare stuff?
أشياء نادرة؟
He means Dorakura-sensei's prized "Dracula Collection,"
،يقصد "مقتنيات دراكولا" القيّمة لدوراكورا سينسي
full of props and costumes from vampire films.
المليئة بأدوات وأزياء من أفلام مصّاصي الدماء
Let's go see, Ran-neechan!
!لنذهب يا ران-نيتشان
I think I'll--
...أنا سأمتنع
C'mon!
!تعالي
His vast collection of props and films are kept in here.
توجد هنا مجموعته الواسعة من الأدوات والأفلام
Hey, where do these stairs go?
أخبرني، أين تؤدي هذه الأدراج؟
Oh, there's a library in the basement.
توجد مكتبة في القبو
It's filled with vampire books and old texts from around the world.
إنّها تعجّ بكتب عن مصّاصي دماء ونصوص قديمة من أرجاء العالم
A Dracula Library, you could call it.
يمكنك تسميتها بمكتبة دراكولا
Whoa, a Dracula mask!
!قناع دراكولا
A Dracula hand!
!يد دراكولا
A cross sword!
!سيف متقاطع
Yes, this one'll do.
حسناً، سأختار هذا
Have you decided on a movie?
هل حدّدتَ فيلماً؟
Yes. An old British movie called Banquet of Fresh Blood.
أجل، فيلم بريطانيّ قديم يُدعى بمأدبة الدم الطازج
He just loves this one!
يحبّه سينسي كثيراً
See that wooden stake there?
أترين الوتد الخشبيّ هناك؟
It was driven through the vampire's heart in the last scene of this film.
تمّ غرسه في قلب مصّاص الدماء في المشهد الأخير لهذا الفيلم
In his study, he also has the cross the vampire was strung up on.
لديه في مكتبه الصليب الذي كان مصّاص الدماء مثبّتاً عليه أيضاً
Huh? I smell oil paint...
...ماذا؟ أشتمّ رائحة طلاء زيتيّ
That's odd. There aren't any oil paintings...
غريب، لا توجد لوحات زيتية
Well, let's go back.
هيّا، لنرجع
Okay!
حسناً
Oh, Ran-san.
ران-سان
Sorry to ask, but could you make sure all the windows are locked?
المعذرة، لكن هلّا تحقّقتِ من أقفال النوافذ؟
Sure, no problem!
أجل، لا مشكلة
They're locked!
إنّها مقفلة
Thanks!
شكراً
What did you think of the Dracula Collection?
ما كان رأيك بمقتنيات دراكولا؟
It was kind of gross!
كانت تبعث على الاشمئزاز نوعاً ما
That sounds interesting.
يبدو ذلك مثيراً للاهتمام
I need to use the restroom. I've been feeling ill since this morning.
عليّ الذهاب للحمّام قليلاً، أشعر بتوعّك في معدتي منذ الصباح
Sure, go ahead.
تفضّل
Sorry.
آسف
Dad. We're going to bed now.
أبي، سنخلد للنوم الآن
You do that. It's grownup time now.
لتناما، هذا وقت البالغين
Huh? That's weird.
ماذا؟ غريب
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
He won't answer the phone.
لا يجيب سينسي على الهاتف
You think maybe he dozed off?
لعلّه غفى
He'd never do that! Late nights and alcohol never affect him!
،ذلك غير معقول بالنسبة لسينسي فقد كان السهر والشراب لا يأثّران عليه
I'll go have a look.
سأذهب لتفقّده
I'll go with him.
سأرافقه إذاً
Sensei! Say something!
!سينسي! أجب رجاءً
Dorakura-sensei!
!دوراكورا سينسي
Sensei!
!سينسي
It's locked.
إنّه مقفل
What's all the noise?
لمَ هذه الجلبة؟
Ma'am! Your husband isn't responding to us!
!سيّدتي! زوجك لا يجيب مهما طرقنا
Oh, that's strange.
هذا غريب
I can hear the projector!
أسمع صوت جهاز العرض
That can't be! Shouldn't the movie be long over by now?!
لا يمكن! ألا يُفترض أنّ الفيلم قد انتهى بهذا الوقت؟
Let's go outside and call for him from the window.
لنخرج وننادي عليه من النافذة
Right!
!حسناً
It's cold!
!الجوّ بارد
The window's open.
النافذة مفتوحة
Only the snow by the window's been trampled on!
!وحده الثلج أمام النافذة به آثار أقدام
What's going on?!
ما الخطب؟
Dorakura-san! Are you in here?!
دوراكورا-سان، أأنت هنا؟
W-What the...
...هـ-هذا
W-What is it?!
!ما-ما الأمر؟
What's going on?!
!ما الذي يجري؟
All the windows, but the one we entered from, are fixed in place.
كلّ النوافذ موصدة باستثناء التي دخلنا منها
And...
...و
the only door is locked from the inside.
الباب الوحيد مقفل من الداخل
Rubber sealing...
...حاجز مطّاطي
It'd be impossible to use string to lock it from the outside.
سيكون من المستحيل استعمال خيط لقفله من الخارج
It would appear the killer entered and exited through that window.
يبدو أنّ القاتل دخل من تلك النافذة
But, Mori-san, how did the killer get here?
لكن يا موري-سان، كيف وصل القاتل هنا؟
Only the snow in front of the window was trampled...
آثار المشي كانت على الثلج أمام النافذة فقط
there were no other footprints.
لم تكن هناك آثار أقدام أخرى
Climbing up the cliff would be impossible,
صعود هذا الجرف سيكون مستحيلاً
and the rough waves in the lake would quickly capsize any boat.
كما أنّ الأمواج الهائجة في البحيرة ستقلب أيّ قارب فوراً
So, even with the window open,
...ما يعني أنّ هذا المكتب
this study room was still as good as locked...
كان بحكم المقفول، حتّى والنافذة مفتوحة
What did the police say?
ماذا عن الشرطة؟
It's no good!
لا جدوى
The snowstorm caused an avalanche that blocked the only road here!
سبّبت العاصفة الثلجية انهياراً مساء اليوم سدّ الطريق المؤدي هنا
They say they can't clear the road until at least morning!
قالوا أنّهم لا يستطيعون فتح الطريق حتّى الصباح
Damn... Looks like I'll have to examine the body...
يا إلهي... يبدو أنّ عليّ فحص الجثّة بنفسي
What a vulgar murderer,
يا للمجرم الشنيع
killing him with a wooden stake, as if he were Dracula...
قتله بوتدٍ خشبيّ كما لو كان دراكولا
...and sticking his body on a cross, on top of that.
وثبّت جثّته على صليب فوق ذلك
Hold on, now!
...تمهل
Why did the killer move the projector and light up the body?!
لمَ حرّك القاتل جهاز العرض وسلّط النور على الجثّة؟
Is there some reason behind it?!
أهناك معنى لهذا؟
It's almost like the last scene of Banquet of Fresh Blood.
كأنّه المشهد الأخير من مأدبة الدم الطازج
Banquet of Fresh Blood?
مأدبة الدم الطازج؟
That's the movie Tadokoro-san brought him!
!ذاك الفيلم الذي جلبه تادوكورو-سان
T-That's right!
!صـ-صحيح
It was Dorakura-sensei's most beloved vampire film.
كان فيلم مصّاص دماء الأقرب لقلب دوراكورا سينسي
So, the killer set it up to look like the movie's last scene?!
أي جعل القاتل جريمته تشبه المشهد الأخير من الفيلم؟
Rigor mortis has set in.
بدأ تصلّب الجثّة
Meaning he's probably been dead for at least an hour.
هذا يعني أنّه مضت ساعة على موته على الأقل
In short, the time of the murder was between 9:00 and 11:00 pm.
ما يعني أنّ وقت الجريمة كان بين التاسعة والحادية عشرة ليلاً عندما كان في مكتبه
There's a wound on the back of his head.
يوجد جرح على مؤخرة رأسه
He must've been hit with this. There's some blood on it.
لا بدّ أنّه ضُرب بهذه، يوجد دم عليها
I see.
فهمت
He was strung up and impaled with the stake after being knocked out.
تم تثبيته بعدما أُفقد وعيه، ثمّ طُعن بالوتد
Mori-san, that stake came from the collection room!
موري-سان، كان هذا الوتد !في غرفة المقتنيات
What?!
!ماذا؟
In short, the killer snuck in and stole the stake
أي أنّ القاتل تسلّل هنا وسرق الوتد
after Tadokoro-san came to get the movie.
بعدما أتى تادوكورو-سان لأخذ الفيلم
Then, after Tadokoro-san delivered the movie to the study room,
،وبعد تسليم تادوكورو-سان الفيلم في المكتب
the person murdered Mr. Dorakura.
قتل المجرم السيّد دوراكورا
Huh?
ماذا؟
It doesn't smell like oil paint...
زالت رائحة الطلاء الزيتيّ
But all the windows were locked from the inside.
لكن كانت كلّ النوافذ مقفلة من الداخل
There's not a single footprint outside the window.
لا يوجد ولا أثر أقدام واحد خارج النافذة
Which means the killer is an insider!
!ما يعني أنّ القاتل من الداخل
Mister! Look!
!انظر يا عمّ
The end of a twig...
...طرف غصين
That's got nothin' to do with this!
!لا علاقة له بالقضيّة
Hamura-san!
!هامورا-سان
The only one who could've stolen the stake
الوحيد الذي كان قادراً على سرقة الوتد
is you, who went to browse the library.
كان أنت بما أنّك كنت تتصفّح في المكتبة
Yes, that's true.
معك حقّ
But, Mori-san, how exactly did I take the stake to the study?
لكن يا موري-سان، كيف أخذت الوتد للمكتب؟
I would've had to pass through the living room, where you all were.
كان عليّ المرور بغرفة المعيشة حيث كنتم
W-Well...
...ذ-ذلك
There is one way!
!توجد طريقة
What?!
ماذا؟
By going upstairs and walking across the corridor's roof!
عبر الصعود للطابق العلويّ والمشي على سطح الممرّ
You could get to the study that way!
يمكنك الذهاب للمكتب هكذا
Ah.
فهمت
I don't need your help! I already knew that!
!أعرف ذلك دون أن تقول
If I wanted to leave, I would still have to go through the living room.
إذا أردتُ المغادرة فعليّ العبور بغرفة المعيشة مهما حصل
Either way, I couldn't have done it.
الأمر مستحيلٌ عليّ بأيّ شكل
Ma'am.
سيّدتي
Yes?
أجل؟
Your room is above the collection room, yes?
غرفتك فوق غرفة المقتنيات، صحيح؟
Ma'am, you conspired with Hamura-san, didn't you?
سيّدتي، أنتِ شريكة لهامورا-سان، أليس كذلك؟
W-What are you saying, Mori-san?!
!ما-ما الذي تقوله يا موري-سان؟
You could dangle a rope to the collection room window from here.
يمكنك إدلاء حبل لنافذة غرفة المقتنيات من هنا
Hamura-san used it to climb up to your room,
استعمله هامورا-سان للتسلّق لغرفتك
then traversed the corridor roof to reach the study.
ثمّ عبر سطح الممرّ للوصول إلى المكتب
He then scaled the roof there and set down in front of that window.
صعد سطح المكتب بعدها ونزل أمام تلك النافذة
Then, he called out to Mr. Dorakura to let him inside,
،ثمّ نادى على السيّد دوراكورا ليُدخله
then murdered him when he got the chance!
وانتظر فرصته وقتله
He used the same course in reverse to get back.
استعمل نفس المسار للعودة
Am I wrong?
أأنا مخطئ؟
Ridiculous!
!يا للسخافة
Why would Hamura-san and I need to conspire to kill my husband?!
لمَ أتواطأ مع هامورا-سان لقتل زوجي؟
Mr. Dorakura suspected you of having an affair.
كان السيّد دوراكورا يشتبه بخيانتك
Ma'am, were you having an affair with Hamura-san?
سيّدتي، هل شريكك العاطفيّ هامورا-سان؟
W-What makes you think we're--
...أ-أيّ دليل لديك
Etsuko, let's not hide the truth.
إيتسوكو، لنتجنّب التستّر على الحقيقة
Hamura-san!
هامورا-سان
The police would find out right away, anyway.
ستكتشف الشرطة فورما تبدأ التحقيق بأيّ حال
So, you admit it, then?
تعترف إذاً؟
I do. But, we truly love each other!
أجل، لكنّنا نحبّ بعضنا صدقاً
Yeah! Hamura-san is the only one I love!
أجل! هامورا-سان هو الوحيد !الذي أحبّه
I never once loved Dorakura!
!لم يسبق وأن أحببتُ دوراكورا
Then why did you get married?
لمَ تزوّجتِه إذاً؟
Eight years ago, my father's business took a nosedive
قبل ثمانية أعوام، انهارت شركة أبي
and was on the verge of bankruptcy.
وكانت على وشك الإفلاس
Dorakura was an old acquaintance of my father's,
كان دوراكورا أحد معارف أبي القدماء
and in exchange for financing the business,
،ومقابل تمويل الشركة
he demanded my hand in marriage after I had just graduated college!
طلب يدي للزواج فورما تخرّجتُ من الجامعة
If the company went bankrupt,
،إذا أفلست الشركة
so many people, and families, would be affected!
!سيعاني الكثير من الموظّفين وعائلاتهم
So, I had no choice but to...
...لذا لم يكن بيدي خيار
We later learned that the business' downfall
أدركنا لاحقاً أنّ انهيار الشركة
was actually because of Dorakura's behind-the-scenes dirty work.
بسبب مكر دوراكورا وراء الكواليس
But, by the time we found out, the company was already in his name,
لكن عند اكتشافنا ذلك، كانت الشركة باسمه بالفعل
and he threatened to destroy the company if we divorced...
...وهدّد بإسقاطها إذا تطلّقنا
That's horrible!
...لا يُعقل
I see.
فهمت
If Mr. Dorakura died, his wife would inherit his company...
إذا مات السيّد دوراكورا، سترث زوجته الشركة
So, that's why you...
...لذا
No! It wasn't us!
!كلا! لم يكن نحن
Do you have proof that we killed him?
ألديك دليلٌ على أنّنا قتلناه؟
Very well. If that's how you want it, then I'll show you.
حسنٌ، إذا كنتما تنكران لهذا الحدّ فسأريكما
You left her room, climbed onto the corridor roof from this window,
غادرت غرفة السيّدة ونزلت لسطح الممرّ من نافذة الرواق هذه
and went to the study.
وذهبتَ للمكتب
The old guy's on the ball today!
!العمّ حادٌ اليوم
Which is why Hamura-san's footprints are still on the roof!
لذا لا تزال آثار أقدام هامورا-سان !على السطح هنا
T-There aren't any footprints!
!لـ-ليست هنا! لا آثار
Say what?!
ماذا؟
That's impossible!
!مستحيل
There's not a single footprint!
!لا يوجد أيّ أثر أقدام
With the corridor unusable, this roof was the only way to the study!
مع عدم إمكانيّة استعمال الممرّ !كان هذا السطح هو الطريق الوحيد للمكتب
Don't tell me the killer actually flew through the air, like a vampire?!
...أيمكن أنّ القاتل طار في السماء حقّاً
Leave the rest to me, old guy!
دع الباقي لي يا عمّ
First, I thought only Hamura-san could have taken the stake,
بدايةً، ظننتُ أنّ هامورا-سان هو ،الوحيد القادر على أخذ الوتد
but actually, anyone could have stolen it from outside!
لكن كان يمكن لأيّ أحد سرقته من الخارج في الواقع
Anyone?
لأيّ أحد؟
There were no footprints because the killer walked through the air.
لم تكن هناك آثار أقدام لأنّ القاتل مشى على الهواء
Walked through the air?
مشى على الهواء؟
On the next Conan: "The Dracula Manor Murder Case (Part 2)."
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Paint.
طلاء تلوين
Next episode dad displays some impressive detective skills.
!في الحلقة القادمة سيبرع أبي باستنتاجاته
Don't you mean impressive sleeping skills?
ألا تقصدين يبرع بنومه؟